A lot of online marketing revolves around
很多线上营销都希望得到潜在客户的直接回应
We'll show them an advertisement, a tweet,
我们会给他们看一段广告、推文、邮件促销
or a special offer via an email and then measure
然后通过点击率和之后的转化率
success based on the click and the subsequent conversion.
才衡量成功与否
This is what's referred to as last click attribution.
这就是我们常说的末次点击归因模型
The entire value of the customers conversion is placed on
将价值100%归因给购买或者转化之前
the marketing channel or campaign that delivered that customer.
最后一次接触的渠道
Last click attribution is easy to measure,
末次点击归因比较好衡量
because it involves a very clear process that the user takes.
因为它简化了客户旅程（比如 看到邮件&gt;点击邮件&gt;转化）
However, this is typically a very flawed method.
但实际上这个方法是非常不准确的
We know that customers take a much larger journey.
客户旅程通常要复杂的多
So it's irresponsible if we focus our marketing analytics efforts on that last click.
所以只关注最后的点击量 是不负责任的
The path the customer takes through your funnel could be a loop,
客户通过你的漏斗时 路径可能是循环式的、
a spiral, a zigzag, and so on.
螺旋上升的、Z 型的 等等
They can dart in and out of your funnels and others seem to just appear.
他们可以随时进入或者退出漏斗 可以突然出现
The time they spend at each step is variable and
他们花在每一个步骤上的时间都不定
some consumers may inexplicably spend time in each step simultaneously.
有一些客户可能会同时在多个步骤出现
Perhaps they're hovering over the checkout button while reassessing whether they're sure,
比如 他们的鼠标停在购物车的结算页面 但实际上心里面在重新考虑
they're in the right place.
是否要在你家购买这些产品
We can't perfectly model human behavior with
一个平面漏斗或者客户旅程
a two-dimensional image of a funnel or the customer journey. Think about it this way.
都不是对客户行为的好的模型构建 可以这样理解：
Have you ever tried to use a different brands loyalty card at a grocery store.
你有没有出现过这样的情况？
So you're at one store and you're trying to use the card for another or
在一家超市 但却用另一家超市的会员卡？
perhaps you put in your branded gas card at the wrong gas station.
或者在错误的加油站用了你的品牌油卡？
You're now immediately aware that you've trick yourself into
发生的时候 你就会马上意识到
going down the wrong path to purchase at the wrong place.
自己的购买路径出错了
You've ignored the signs but it's almost the same thing.
你会选择忽略这些信号 但实际结果是一样的
Then you toss your loyalty out the window and make the purchase anyway.
你会把会员卡扔掉 然后还是在这家超市买了东西
What I'm getting at is that the customer path is really illogical,
好吧 我想说的是客户旅程很多时候是没有逻辑的
and if you really start to think about
如果你要认真考虑
all the various avenues by which a customer comes to purchase,
客户完成购买的所有不同路径
it's going to be really complex.
就真的很复杂了
That's why when it comes to marketing analytics,
所以在市场分析里
we need to simplify it by thinking about things as they
我们只需要将客户所想的过程简化
relate to the buyer's mindset and how that maps to our funnel.
以及这些思考过程如何对应着我们的漏斗
Our goal is just to look at the most common paths.
我们的目标是只看最常见的客户路径
We're setting everything up with our analytics in
我们分析的时候
anticipation of a user going through each step,
实际上是预设了用户会通过漏斗的每一步
and when we do this we'll capture the majority.
这样就可以抓取到大部分客户
We'll be ready to measure those who zig and those who zag,
至于那些不寻常的客户路径
and we'll let the analytics tools fill in the gaps.
分析工具会帮助我们捕捉和填补
We're not terribly concerned if a user skips
我们不需要太担心一个用户是否跳过了某个博客
a blog article or if they didn't sign up for our email campaign.
或者没有订阅邮件
So long as they have the opportunity,
只要确保这些都触达到了他们
we measured it, and that they eventually make that purchase.
我们进行了展现量的衡量以及对他们的购买的计数 就行了
So the framework by which we're evaluating the buyer, this marketing funnel,
因此 我们用来衡量用户行为的框架 即这个营销漏斗
this journey is meant to be flexible,
或者客户旅程 应该是灵活的
and it's meant to be measured in a flexible manner.
衡量方式也应该是灵活的
We really just want to describe the most common path.
我们关注的应该是大多数客户的路径
So don't feel overwhelmed if you can't attribute
所以 你不用太担心无法衡量每一个
a measurement for every possible journey or touch point.
可能的客户路径或者触点
Your goal is to cover the big picture.
你的目标是描述大多数的情况
In doing so, you're still going to support
而且 你仍然可以包括那些在漏斗里跳来跳去的
the erratic customer who bounces around your funnel like a pinball.
奇怪的客户行为
We call what we're building the reference experience.
我们构建的典型路径叫做 参考体验 (reference experience)
That is how the customer wants to navigate,
即 符合你的目标人群的一个典型客户
not necessarily how you're currently set up for
会怎样在网站上进行浏览
the average customer in your target segment.
不一定是你目前的网站设置
So when it comes to picking data across the journey,
接下来 我们会讲如何
which we're going to do in a bit,
从不同的客户旅程阶段抓取数据
just think about the most simplified and most common paths.
这里的客户旅程即是简化后的、最典型的路径